I know this looks like drugs, but we're
building a cabinet bed. Today, I'm going
to build a cabinet bed. You see what I
had in my head? I've never built a
cabinet bed before.
We're all going to get to learn
together, but I got to solve the storage
problem. I don't have a closet anywhere
in this room. What I'm going to do is
use these pipes to make rollers
underneath my bed. I want to be able to
build something out of easily attained
building materials. That way, anybody on
planet Earth can make a cabinet bed from
their local hardware store. Materials
needed. These are going to be the
runners for my bed. This is going to be
the inside part that's going to house
these. What I'm going to do is cut
these. I'm going to set those up like
this. And then these are going to be my
bed slats across the top. So, I'm going
to have a cavity here of about 2 ft. I'm
going to reap these down and place them
in between and drill holes in them.
Then, I'm going to slide this 1/2 in
pipe through. And I cut this about 2 and
1/2 in shorter. This is 26 in. This is
23 in. And that'll slide in. It'll sit
inside of these two runner boards. And
then these will spin freely with the
help. A little old WD30. That's my plan.
Cabinet bed. Take one.
I think I'm just going to have to chisel
that guy. Look, that's a perfect
straight line. I'm going to have to have
that to square off of.
All right. Got to be nice and straight.
I think I need to let the side runners
go longer. That way when the drawer
comes out, it'll want to kick down and
if I have a longer part, that'll give me
some cany lever in the back. That's the
end. It just needs something to keep it
up in the back. I have a little bit of
wiggle room cuz my smallest hole saw
it's a little bigger. So, I think I'll
be okay. I got about an eighth inch of
play.
How big are we going to make this
drawer? It's going to be this wide.
Exactly. This is 23 and 12. It's a
quarter inch of room for this to be able
to spin. So if we have 48 in divided by
9 cuz I have eight rollers, that's going
to be five. So about every five 3 in
divided by 9. Take 3 in, that's going to
be about what? A third of an inch. So we
just say 38.
How wide does this drawer need to be?
That's going to be the top. And I have a
little bit of clearance here. I'm going
to screw these on the inside of that.
5/8 of an inch gap. Now, I'm going to
have to drill a hole right here for
this. And I'm going to set this on the
ground. That way, it's got some ass to
support it. So, how wide do you think?
Is a 4 and 1/2 in drawer tall enough?
That is undoubtedly a straight line.
It's real easy to buy some [__] and just
put it together. Y'all know that, right?
But going left, right, to left is like
taking a piss with somebody else's dick.
OH.
WOO!
>> I told you not to touch it.
>> It went I didn't touch it. It went in my
[__] pan. How do you know it's hot? I
know how hot it is. That [__] was real
hot.
Last one would have been real easy with
some modern tools from America. But I'm
using a [__] 3/4 in hole saw and a
paddle bit to finish it out.
If it worked, this will pass right
through it.
Hey. Okay, let's put it together. Making
sure there's not a bow in it. I can't
wobble it. And there is a bow in them. I
hopefully I just got it turned up. I
like to be on the other side of the line
so I can see it.
Okay, these are even, right? I need
these to be a little bit shorter. This
is going to be my runner and then that's
going to sit on the inside. All I got to
do now is screw it together. I need
something to nail this to. That ain't
really going to cut it.
Now I can cut some the right length. Use
these trim nails to hold it in place.
Then I can tap it around a little bit if
I need to. Then I'll come back and put
some screws in it later.
Now the other one.
Moment of truth. Ola. Huh.
All right. All right. All right. I need
to make these 25 in, 23 and 1/2. So I
need to make this about 23 and 5/8 or 23
and 3/4. That'll give me a/4 in of play
on each side or is an eighth an inch all
we want. That way we can put it on there
and the drawer will just roll right on
in pipes.
So we have all that
one. Look, there we go. Now that's
perfect. glued screwed tattoos never to
be undoed.
For the back, I'm going to use a little
bit bigger piece cuz I want to lock
something in like this. It's a lot of
thinking, man. 26 and a just a touch
more. Shout out to John Pilgrim for the
new saw blades.
I have a nail gun that I can use for
this, but it'll split the hell out of
that wood. There you go.
>> That's a bad for y'all.
>> Now, we got to square it up, though. You
got to pull your diagonals. 79 and 1116.
80 and 12.
And now we are 80 and 316. See that one?
>> Let's see. That's 80. 80 and a6.
80 and a 16th. 80 and a 16th. Since it's
square, I'm going to go ahead and put
one of these on the back to LOCK IT IN.
GOING TO HAVE A 4FT CABINET, RIGHT?
>> MHM.
>> It's 4ft level. Does it look like it's
passing freely?
>> Mhm.
>> All we need is this thing to come in and
out. Now I need to build a drawer. This
is going to be my drawer. I got them
squared up. I got 23 in drawer.
More l This is finished. It came from
the saw up the road.
Let's see how she rides.
Bam, that fit well.
Still got to put a base on it. And I
think I'm going to use the same tongue
and groove teak and Laurel. I use this
teak and it'll lock together and make
this thing really straight. Now I got to
nail a whole bunch of teak on the back
of this. Yay.
Building my drawer right here. Show be a
lot faster with a miter saw. I got to
mark everyone by hand. Cut it by hand
again.
I'm here to tell you, I can cut like a
damn like a miter saw with a skill saw
now. And I really prefer to cut [__]
like this now. Just eyeball it and kind
OF
cut them off
for a drawer. Pretty heavy. Now you see
what I had in my head where I got to put
the face on it. I think we should put
cedar on the front. Or do you want it to
be loud out with the red cedar match the
colors? Always got to pilot something
out if you don't want it to strip.
It's pretty cool cuz look, this just
sits on the ground cuz all I got to do
is put some screws in this. See how
that's already coming apart? And then
lock it all in really tight. Time to
screw this whole thing off.
Last part.
Oh [__] I think I did it on my very
first try. Do I look like a genius? No.
Do I feel like a genius? Yes. I'm
putting a mattress on this thing in a
minute. You don't understand. I'm going
to sleep in here tonight.
I have built me a cabinet bed. Doesn't
this look rewarding?
I'm telling you, you'd probably be
happier to watch somebody build a
cabinet bed than build one yourself.
This might be the first and last cabinet
bed I ever built in my life. Limited
edition. Tired. Joe is out.